export const ECONOMICSA2008 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. The problem of humanity has always been that its wants",
A: "cannot be prioritized.",
B: "are unlimited.",
C: "are scarce.",
D: "can only be produced technologically.",
answer: "B. are unlimited.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. Opportunity cost in economics implies that a person",
A: "has the chance to minimize costs.",
B: "has to forgo one thing in order to have another.",
C: "can equate his fixed costs with his variable costs.",
D: "is able to run his business efficiently.",
answer: "B. has to forgo one thing in order to have another.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. A three-sector economy is made up of households, firms and",
A: "government.",
B: "capital.",
C: "labour.",
D: "entrepreneur.",
answer: "A. government.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. Which one of the following is a tool of economic analysis?",
A: "Costs",
B: "Graphs",
C: "Concepts",
D: "Theories",
answer: "D. Theories",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. The most frequently occurring value in a given data is the",
A: "mode.",
B: "mean.",
C: "median.",
D: "range.",
answer: "A. mode.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. Which of the following is classified under primary activity?",
A: "Manufacturing",
B: "Insurance",
C: "Fashion designing",
D: "Fishing",
answer: "D. Fishing",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. A benefit of large-scale production to a firm is that",
A: "there is rise in advertising expenditure.",
B: "consumers receive a share of the profits.",
C: "the firm can use labour-saving machinery.",
D: "demand for the firm’s products becomes localized.",
answer: "C. the firm can use labour-saving machinery.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. An economic system exists to",
A: "provide organizations needed to satisfy wants.",
B: "ensure that all people are treated equally.",
C: "give individuals the power to control the economy.",
D: "provide funds for investment.",
answer: "A. provide organizations needed to satisfy wants.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. The pursuit of profits and private ownership of property are common features of",
A: "socialism.",
B: "individualism.",
C: "communism.",
D: "capitalism.",
answer: "D. capitalism.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. Diminishing marginal utility means that as more units of a good are purchased the",
A: "benefit from an extra unit decreases.",
B: "benefit from an extra unit increases.",
C: "total benefits derived from the good decreases.",
D: "marginal benefit derived from the good is constant.",
answer: "A. benefit from an extra unit decreases.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. Which of the following is a variable cost to a firm?",
A: "Payment for electrical fittings",
B: "Expenditure on machinery",
C: "Payment for raw materials",
D: "Rent on factory land",
answer: "C. Payment for raw materials",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. Average productivity per worker is the total output",
A: "added to the number of workers.",
B: "divided by the number of workers.",
C: "subtracted from the number of workers.",
D: "multiplied by the number of workers.",
answer: "B. divided by the number of workers.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. The graph of the function 5q = 20 – P is a",
A: "demand graph.",
B: "supply graph.",
C: "cost graph.",
D: "revenue graph.",
answer: "A. demand graph.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. Change in quantity demanded implies a",
A: "shift in demand curve to the right.",
B: "shift in demand curve to the left.",
C: "movement along the same demand curve.",
D: "fall in price and quantity demanded.",
answer: "C. movement along the same demand curve.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. The demand associated with labour is called",
A: "joint demand.",
B: "derived demand.",
C: "composite demand.",
D: "competitive demand.",
answer: "B. derived demand.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. An inferior good is a commodity whose demand",
A: "falls as income increases.",
B: "remains constant as income increases.",
C: "rises as income increases.",
D: "remains constant as income falls.",
answer: "A. falls as income increases.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. Commodities which are used for further production are known as",
A: "final goods.",
B: "normal goods.",
C: "producer goods.",
D: "consumer goods.",
answer: "C. producer goods.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. The supply of a commodity is represented by the function Qs = 35 + ¾ P. At a supply level of 50 units the price of the commodity in dollars",
A: "9.",
B: "12.",
C: "20.",
D: "35.",
answer: "C. 20.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. The backward bending labour supply curve means that",
A: "as wage rate increases, the quantity of labour supplied rises.",
B: "as wage rate increases, the quantity of labour supplied falls.",
C: "the quantity of labour supplied has reached a maximum.",
D: "the quantity of labour demanded increases.",
answer: "B. as wage rate increases, the quantity of labour supplied falls.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. Supply is elastic when the coefficient is",
A: "zero.",
B: "negative.",
C: "greater than one.",
D: "less than one.",
answer: "C. greater than one.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. Price control aimed at protecting consumers is fixed",
A: "at demand price.",
B: "below equilibrium.",
C: "at supply price.",
D: "above equilibrium.",
answer: "B. below equilibrium.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. Labour force is the",
A: "total population less the number of old people.",
B: "total population less the number of children.",
C: "adult population.",
D: "working population.",
answer: "D. working population.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. One of the ways of discouraging rural-urban drift is to",
A: "establish higher institutions of learning in the cities.",
B: "provide the rural areas with infrastructures.",
C: "establish capital markets in large towns.",
D: "improve facilities in the cities.",
answer: "B. provide the rural areas with infrastructures.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. Unemployment due to physical disability is referred to as",
A: "cyclical unemployment.",
B: "residual unemployment.",
C: "frictional unemployment.",
D: "structural unemployment.",
answer: "B. residual unemployment.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. One of the economic consequences of increase in the dependent population is that it",
A: "increases the standard of living.",
B: "makes the per capita income static.",
C: "makes the working population less productive.",
D: "reduces the per capita income.",
answer: "D. reduces the per capita income.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. If output more than doubles when input is doubled, the firm is said to be experiencing",
A: "returns to scale.",
B: "normal profit in production.",
C: "increasing returns to scale.",
D: "constant returns to scale.",
answer: "C. increasing returns to scale.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. Industrialization will be encouraged by the level of",
A: "trade union activities.",
B: "unemployment.",
C: "co-operation.",
D: "savings and investment.",
answer: "D. savings and investment.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. One of the major criticisms against the middleman is that of",
A: "excessive profiteering.",
B: "delaying production activities.",
C: "misinforming consumers about the qualities of their goods.",
D: "bridging the gap between the producer and the consumer.",
answer: "A. excessive profiteering.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. The problems militating against the smooth distribution of goods in West Africa include",
A: "poor transport facilities.",
B: "effective price monitoring.",
C: "provision of storage facilities.",
D: "inadequate demand for essential commodities.",
answer: "A. poor transport facilities.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. Subsidy may become necessary when the supply of a commodity is",
A: "elastic.",
B: "adequate.",
C: "insufficient.",
D: "indeterminable.",
answer: "C. insufficient.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. A business unit organized for the mutual benefits of members with similar interests is known as a",
A: "co-operative society.",
B: "public corporation.",
C: "limited liability company.",
D: "partnership.",
answer: "A. co-operative society.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. Who performs the risk-bearing function of the entrepreneur in a public limited company? The",
A: "government.",
B: "leaders.",
C: "workers.",
D: "shareholders.",
answer: "D. shareholders.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. Dividend paid by public limited companies is based on",
A: "patronage.",
B: "price of the share.",
C: "profit declared.",
D: "the rate of turnover.",
answer: "C. profit declared.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. A higher proportion of West African labour force is engaged in the agricultural sector because the",
A: "agricultural sector is the highest contributor of foreign exchange.",
B: "agricultural sector provides raw materials for industries.",
C: "economy is relatively under-developed.",
D: "income in the agricultural sector is high.",
answer: "C. economy is relatively under-developed.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. Which of the following should a monopolist do to increase his sales?",
A: "Move to another market",
B: "Increase supply",
C: "Reduce expenditure",
D: "Lower price",
answer: "D. Lower price",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. The desire to hold money to meet unexpected occurrences is the",
A: "future motive.",
B: "precautionary motive.",
C: "transaction motive.",
D: "speculative motive.",
answer: "B. precautionary motive.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. Central banks in British West Africa were preceded by",
A: "co-operativc banks.",
B: "rural banks.",
C: "currency board.",
D: "mortgage banks.",
answer: "C. currency board.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. West African countries collect taxes because",
A: "the prices of commodities are rising.",
B: "people tend to hold more money.",
C: "individuals prefer leisure to work.",
D: "of the need to finance public projects.",
answer: "D. of the need to finance public projects.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. The budget for the payment of workers’ salaries is",
A: "recurrent budget.",
B: "annual budget.",
C: "capital budget.",
D: "supplementary budget.",
answer: "A. recurrent budget.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. Revenue will increase by taxing commodities whose elasticity of demand is",
A: "infinite.",
B: "inelastic.",
C: "elastic.",
D: "unitary.",
answer: "B. inelastic.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. Consumption is mainly determined by the size of the",
A: "market.",
B: "firm.",
C: "labour force.",
D: "income.",
answer: "D. income.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. It is necessary to estimate the national income of a country because it",
A: "indicates the overall performance of the economy.",
B: "ensures equitable distribution of wealth.",
C: "assists investors to earn more profits.",
D: "enables governments to generate revenue efficiently.",
answer: "A. indicates the overall performance of the economy.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. Which of the following will be included in the national income estimate?",
A: "Grants to students",
B: "Services of housewives",
C: "A house built and occupied by the owner",
D: "Remittances to one’s parents",
answer: "C. A house built and occupied by the owner",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. Appreciable increase in per capita income reveals that the standard of living is",
A: "low.",
B: "average.",
C: "rising.",
D: "constant.",
answer: "C. rising.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. Economic planning is undertaken mainly to promote",
A: "inflation.",
B: "unemployment.",
C: "foreign investment.",
D: "rapid development.",
answer: "D. rapid development.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. One of the characteristics of developing countries is",
A: "high technology.",
B: "high illiteracy.",
C: "general affluence.",
D: "adequate infrastructure.",
answer: "B. high illiteracy.",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. Net export is a positive figure when a country’s",
A: "stock of goods is declining.",
B: "imports exceed exports.",
C: "imports are adjusted upwards.",
D: "exports exceed imports.",
answer: "D. exports exceed imports.",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. The official reduction in the value of a country’s currency in relation to other foreign currencies is called",
A: "over-valuation.",
B: "under-valuation.",
C: "devaluation.",
D: "revaluation.",
answer: "C. devaluation.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. Balance of payments comprise",
A: "three interrelated accounts.",
B: "four interrelated accounts.",
C: "seven interrelated accounts.",
D: "ten interrelated accounts.",
answer: "A. three interrelated accounts.",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. The International Monetary Fund (IMF) has its headquarters in",
A: "Nigeria.",
B: "Ghana.",
C: "United States of America.",
D: "Japan.",
answer: "C. United States of America.",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},


]